Draper Corporation Glass Plate Negatives 6612 GPN
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Series B: 8 x 10 inch negatives.
  - Draper Company horse with handler, 1903 (Box 130, Folder 61)
    Negative no.B61. Image depicts a Draper Company horse posed outside the same stone building (on the right) seen in Box 129, Negative 50. The horse is black (or dark colored); posed next to him is a dark-haired man wearing dark pants with suspenders, a white shirt and a very large tie. The horse is probably the same one seen in Box 129, Negative 51 and Negative 58. The man is the same one as the man seen on the right in Box 129, Negative 50. The horse is probably one of the horses owned by the Draper Company for pulling carts and wagons. Several residential buildings are visible in the background. 8 x 10 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 12, Folder 3, Item 61 for print of this negative.
  - Draper Company horse with handler, 1903 (Box 130, Folder 62)
    Negative no.B62-A. Image depicts a Draper Company horse posed outside the same stone building seen in Box 129, Negative 50. The horse is black (or dark colored); his rein is being held by a man on the left, wearing a white shirt and white pants. He holds his straw hat in his right hand, possibly to attract the horse's attention so the horse will pose with his head up. The man has a mustache but does not appear to be either of the two men seen in Box 129, Negative 50, however, both this man and horse can also be seen in Box 129, Negative 59. The horse is probably one of the horses owned by the Draper Company for pulling carts and wagons. The man could be a cart or wagon driver. Several residential buildings are visible in the background. 8 x 10 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 12, Folder 3, Item 62 for print of this negative.
  - Ballou Park with statue of Adin Ballou, 1903 (Box 130, Folder 67)
    Negative no.B67-A. Image depicts Ballou Park, sometimes referred to as Adin Ballou Park, showing flowering trees, bushes, park benches (on either side of the statue and in the left background), and a bronze statue of Adin Ballou, the founder of the Hopedale Community. The statue was unveiled in October 1900 and is located on the Ballou property; it was the gift of Gen. W. F. Draper. In 1900 the Ballou house was moved from this site and the park established. In the foreground is an unpaved street with trolley tracks; another unpaved street runs off it into the right background. See also Box 22, Negative 330 and Box 25, Negative 399. Original photograph by the Draper Company. 8 x 10 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 12, Folder 3, Item 67 for print of this negative.
  - Two Draper Company horses with handler, 1903 (Box 130, Folder 68)
    Negative no.B68. Image depicts one man holding the reins of two horses, presumed to be Draper Company horses. Both horses are black or dark colored. The man wears a vest, tie and hat; he has a mustache and dark curly hair. He is probably a cart or wagon driver for Draper. The stone building on the right is unidentified but is possibly the Bancroft Memorial Library. Several residential buildings can be seen in the background. This man can also be seen in Box 129, Negative 50 and Negative 61, in this box. See Box 129, Negative 50, Negative 51, Negative 52, Negative 58, and Negative 59, and Negative 61, in this box, for other images of Draper horses. 8 x 10 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 12, Folder 3, Item 68 for print of this negative.
  - Howard W. Bracken House (Box 130, Folder 72)
    Negative no.B72. 1894-1900. Image depicts the Howard W. Bracken House in Hopedale, Massachusetts, also known as the Lilla (Bancroft) Bracken Pratt House. The house is a substantial two-and-a-half story wood clapboard building with an extension on the right, two visible chimneys, shutters at all the windows, and a front porch that stretches the length of the front and extends on either side. Howard W. Bracken was the husband of Lilla Bancroft and the son-in- law of Joseph and Sylvia Bancroft. The 1904 town directory lists Bracken as the Draper foundry superintendent, living on Hopedale Street, near Peace - the house across from the Bancroft Library. Original photograph by the Draper Company. 8 x 10 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 12, Folder 3, Item 72 for print of this negative.
  - Bancroft Memorial Library (Box 130, Folder 77)
    Negative no.B77. 1898-1900. Image depicts a stone building with an arched doorway and windows. Viewed from this angle, the library appears to have two floors, with the lower floor partially underground. This is a different view than that seen in Box 23, Negative 352, which shows the fountain at the far left (not seen here). The library was donated to the town in 1898 by Joseph Bancroft, a Draper Company executive, in memory of his wife, Sylvia. The building was designed by Boston architect C. Howard Walker. It is constructed of Milford granite, and was modeled after Merton College Chapel at Oxford. See Negative 78, in this box, Box 21, Negative 317, and Box 23, Negative 342, and Negative 352 for other views of the library and fountain. Original photograph by the Draper Company. 8 x 10 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 12, Folder 3, Item 77 for print of this negative.
  - Entrance, Bancroft Memorial Library (Box 130, Folder 78)
    Negative no.B78. 1898-1900. Image depicts a stone building with an arched doorway and windows. Viewed from this angle, the library appears to have two floors, with the lower floor partially underground. The fountain seen in Box 23, Negative 352 is not visible here and may not have yet been installed. The library was donated to the town in 1898 by Joseph Bancroft, a Draper Company executive, in memory of his wife, Sylvia. The building was designed by Boston architect C. Howard Walker. It is constructed of Milford granite, and was modeled after Merton College Chapel at Oxford. Trees are bare; photo taken in early spring or late fall. See Negative 77, in this box, Box 21, Negative 317, and Box 23, Negative 342, and Negative 352 for other views of the library and fountain. Original photograph by the Draper Company. 8 x 10 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 12, Folder 3, Item 78 for print of this negative.
  - Bird's eye view of Hopedale, Massachusetts, from Main to Dutcher streets, 1902 (Box 131, Folder 83)
    Negative no.B83. Summer, 1902. Image depicts a bird's eye view of the area of Hopedale, Massachusetts, from Main to Dutcher streets, taken from a high vantage point, possibly from a Draper Company building. Image shows houses scattered throughout the area with trees interspersed. The distant background appears to be mostly trees. No factory buildings visible in this view. Original photograph by the Draper Company. 8 x 10 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 12, Folder 3, Item 83 for print of this negative.
  - Park House (Box 131, Folder 84)
    Negative no.B84. 1894-1900. Image depicts a four-story wooden clapboard house, with shutters at all the windows (a few are closed). A porch stretches across the entire front of the house with two sets of steps to the porch. There is a bay window on the left side, with a back porch beyond it. A sign "Park House" sits above the front porch roof. This is most likely a Draper Company boardinghouse, and looks somewhat similar to Hopedale House. There is a small lawn in front and some new trees have been planted; the house sits at the corner of two streets. Original photograph by the Draper Company. 8 x 10 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 12, Folder 3, Item 84 for print of this negative.
  - Interior of Bancroft Memorial Library (Box 131, Folder 91)
    Negative no.B91. ca. 1903. Image depicts an interior view of the Bancroft Memorial Library in Hopedale, Massachusetts A large, circular wooden desk sits in the center, behind which are rows of wooden bookcases, filled with books. Two card catalogs sit on either side of the room. Wooden railings can be seen on each side (sectioning off other rooms?), and the room has wooden arches and columns. There is a large hanging chandelier with eight lamps, plus wall sconces on the columns. The library was donated to the town in 1898 by Joseph Bancroft, a Draper Company executive, in memory of his wife, Sylvia. The building was designed by Boston architect C. Howard Walker. It is constructed of Milford granite, and was modeled after Merton College Chapel at Oxford. Original photograph by the Draper Company. 8 x 10 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 12, Folder 3, Item 91 for print of this negative. See also, Collection 6612 P, Box 17, Folder 1, Item 91 for print of this negative. See also, Collection 6612 P, Box 17, Folder 4, Item 91.1 and 91.2 for print of this negative.
  - Housing in Prospect Heights, Milford, Massachusetts (Box 131, Folder 99)
    Negative no.B99. 1905? Image depicts a group of two-story brick buildings (although some seem to have at least one floor partially below ground) designed to accommodate two or more families. The buildings' features include multiple chimneys, shutters at each window, and lawns. An open field is in the foreground. There are three children barely visible in the road on the right, and hanging laundry on a clothesline on the left. Prospect Heights was built as housing for Draper Company employees, but most houses in Prospect Heights were brick, as opposed to the wooden housing found in Hopedale, Massachusetts The houses are believed to have been designed by Peabody & Stearns. See Box 22, Negative 339 and Box 23, Negative 347 for views of some of these houses but from a narrower angle. Original photograph by the Draper Company. 8 x 10 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 12, Folder 3, Item 99 for print of this negative.
  - Cluster of houses in Prospect Heights, Milford, Massachusetts (Box 132, Folder 107)
    Negative no.B107. ca. 1905. Image depicts the end of a row of two-story brick buildings on the left. Another row of buildings can be seen behind it. These buildings were designed to accommodate two or more families. The building features include multiple chimneys, shutters at each window (all the shutters are closed on the end house on the left), and small lawns in front. A freestanding clothesline can be seen in the side yard in the center. Note the multiple stairways in the rear of these buildings as well. Several small boys sit or lie on the grass in the center. Open space is visible in the foreground. Prospect Heights was built as housing for Draper Company employees, but most houses in Prospect Heights were brick, as opposed to the wooden housing found in Hopedale, Massachusetts The houses are believed to have been designed by Peabody & Stearns. See Box 22, Negative 335 for a view of the entire row of houses on the left. Original photograph taken by the Draper Company. 8 x 10 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 12, Folder 4, Item 107 for print of this negative.
  - Park House (Box 132, Folder 112)
    Negative no.B112. 1894-1900. Image depicts a four-story wooden clapboard house, with shutters at all the windows (a few are closed). A porch stretches across the entire front of the house with two sets of steps to the porch. There is a bay window on the left side, with a back porch beyond it. A sign "Park House" sits above the front porch roof. This is most likely a Draper Company boardinghouse, and looks somewhat similar to Hopedale House. There is a small lawn in front and some new trees have been planted; the house sits at the corner of two streets. Original photograph by the Draper Company. 8 x 10 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 12, Folder 4, Item 112 for print of this negative.
  - Foundry Dept. (?) office, Draper Company (Box 132, Folder 124)
    Negative no.B124. 1900-1903. Image depicts a view of the interior of an office in the Draper Company, possibly the Foundry Dept. office, given the wooden box stamped "Foundry Dept." under the table on the left. A rolltop desk in the center background is loaded with papers, ledgers, and cubbyholes, also filled with papers. A unit resembling a telephone sits at the edge of the desk, and may be a method of communicating to another office or the dept. floor. The desk to the right of the rolltop desk holds a typewriter and is also filled with papers and ledgers. Framed prints hang on the walls above windows which possibly look over the working floor. The Draper Company manufactured textile machinery, primarily looms. 8 x 10 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 12, Folder 4, Item 124 for print of this negative.
  - Hopedale Street (west side) showing Draper Co. shop and office, 1903 (Box 133, Folder 134)
    Negative no.B134. May 7, 1903. Image depicts a view of the west side of Hopedale Street in Hopedale, Massachusetts, showing the Draper Company shop and office. It is possible the two-story brick building in the center is the office, but it is unclear. That building, and the two-story building directly behind it with the one-story extension to the left all have striped awnings on some of the windows. Larger factory buildings can be seen behind in the background on both sides. A man stands on the sidewalk in front of the center building. Hopedale Street is unpaved, as is the street running perpendicularly in the left foreground, but both have sidewalks. There are a number of trees along the street. A set of trolley tracks runs along Hopedale Street. A water tower is on the top of the building at the left in the background. The Draper Company manufactured textile machinery, primarily looms. See Box 135, Negative 178 for this same view taken nine days later. See Negative 135 and Negative 136, in this box, for views of the buildings on the street to the left of what is shown in this image. Original photograph by the Draper Company. 8 x 10 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 12, Folder 4, Item 134 for print of this negative.
  - Hopedale Street (west side) showing Draper Co. buildings, 1903 (Box 133, Folder 135)
    Negative no.B135. May 7, 1903. Image depicts a view of the west side of Hopedale Street in Hopedale, Massachusetts, showing the Draper Company shop, office, and hose house. It is unclear which building is which, although the one-story building on the right with the striped awnings may be the office. There is a one-story wooden clapboard building with a tower in the center left; in the background are several three- and four-story brick buildings, all part of the Draper Company complex. The sign on the pole in front of the wooden clapboard building reads: "Private Property. Do No Drive In. Very Dangerous." The wooden clapboard building is at a junction of Hopedale and another street, both unpaved. A set of trolley tracks runs along Hopedale Street. A water tower is on the top of the building at the right in the background. The Draper Company manufactured textile machinery, primarily looms. See Negative 136, in this box, for a view of the buildings on the street to the left of what is shown in this image, and Box 134, Negative 165 for a view of the east side of Hopedale Street taken from behind the pole with the sign. See also Box 135, Negative 179. Original photograph by the Draper Company. 8 x 10 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 12, Folder 4, Item 135 for print of this negative.
  - Hopedale Street (west side) showing houses, 1903 (Box 133, Folder 136)
    Negative no.B136. May 7, 1903. Image depicts a view of the west side of Hopedale Street in Hopedale, Massachusetts, showing two residential houses on the left, behind which are Draper Company buildings. Both houses are two-story wooden clapboard buildings with shutters at all the windows; the house nearer the center has an open front porch. Behind the two houses on the right is a three-story building with a tall smokestack, part of the Draper Company complex. The streets are unpaved, but Hopedale Street is lined with trees. Trolley tracks run along Hopedale Street. The unknown cross street has a sidewalk. The Draper Company manufactured textile machinery, primarily looms. See Negative 135, in this box, for a view of the buildings on the street to the right of what is shown in this image. Original photograph by the Draper Company. 8 x 10 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 12, Folder 4, Item 136 for print of this negative. See also, Collection 6612 P, Box 17, Folder 3, Item 136 for print of this negative.
  - Screw Shop interior with workers, Draper Company, 1903 (Box 134, Folder 145)
    Negative no.B145. Image depicts a view of the interior of the Draper Company Screw Shop, showing two male workers at work. Machines line the left-hand wall, and large windows provide illumination. Hanging lamps provide more light if needed. There appears to be sawdust on the floor. The Draper Company manufactured textile machinery, primarily looms, and manufactured some, if not all of the parts, including screws. See Negative 147, in this box, for a view of the shop without any workers visible. 8 x 10 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 12, Folder 4, Item 145 for print of this negative.
  - Interior of Screw Shop, Draper Company, 1903 (Box 134, Folder 147)
    Negative no.B147. Image depicts a view of the interior of the Draper Company Screw Shop. Machines line the left-hand wall, and large windows provide illumination, although the two closest windows appear to have been blocked with paper or some other material. Hanging lamps provide more light if needed. There appears to be sawdust on the floor. The Draper Company manufactured textile machinery, primarily looms, and manufactured some, if not all of the parts, including screws. See Negative 145, in this box, for a view of the shop with two male workers visible. 8 x 10 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 12, Folder 4, Item 147 for print of this negative.
  - Hopedale Street (west side) showing Draper Company buildings in the background, 1903 (Box 134, Folder 150)
    Negative no.B150. May 9, 1903. Image depicts a view of the west side of Hopedale Street in Hopedale, Massachusetts, showing the edge of a residential house on the right and a complex of buildings in the background, two of which are connected by a covered walkway (seen in the center of the photo). Hopedale Street and the street perpendicular to it in the foreground are both unpaved but have sidewalks. Several trees line Hopedale Street. See Negative 151, in this box, for the buildings that appear to the right of what is shown in this image (including the edge of the house on the right). Original photograph by the Draper Company. 8 x 10 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 12, Folder 4, Item 150 for print of this negative.
  - Hopedale Street (west side) showing old fire tower, 1903 (Box 134, Folder 151)
    Negative no.B151. May 9, 1903. Image depicts a view of the west side of Hopedale Street in Hopedale, Massachusetts, showing a residential house on the left, and what may be a barn building of some sort on the right. In the background on the far right is a brick building that is part of the Draper Company complex. Attached to the barn building is a tall tower with a bell at the top; this may be the old fire tower referred to in the caption on the reverse of the print. In the foreground is some open area with grass and bushes; Hopedale Street is lined with trees. See Negative 150, in this box, for a view of the buildings to the left of what is shown in this image. Original photograph by the Draper Company. 8 x 10 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 12, Folder 4, Item 151 for print of this negative.
  - View of Bancroft Memorial Library, 1903 (Box 134, Folder 154)
    Negative no.B154. Image depicts a single-story stone building with an arched doorway and windows. The library was donated to the town in 1898 by Joseph Bancroft, a Draper Company executive, in memory of his wife, Sylvia. The building was designed by Boston architect C. Howard Walker. It is constructed of Milford granite, and was modeled after Merton College Chapel at Oxford. The marble sculptures and fountain seen in Box 23, Negative 352 have apparently not yet been added. See Box 21, Negative 317 for a view of the fountain; see Box 130, Negative 77 and Negative 78, and Box 23, Negative 342, and Negative 352 for other views of the library. Original photograph by the Draper Company. 8 x 10 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 12, Folder 4, Item 154 for print of this negative.
  - Henry Patrick's store (side view), Hopedale Street (west side), 1903 (Box 134, Folder 156)
    Negative no.B156. May 9, 1903. Image depicts a view of the side of Henry Patrick's store in Hopedale, Massachusetts The building is a two-story clapboard, with shutters at some windows and a chimney in the rear. A horse-drawn wagon has been backed up to the door and is loaded with goods; another horse-drawn wagon carrying barrels is in the center of the image. The store was located on the west side of Hopedale Street; the front view of the store would be to the left, outside this image. The Henry L. Patrick store was established in 1869 and was a general country store, stocking all sorts of goods and commodities. The building was torn down in 1966. Original photograph by the Draper Company. 8 x 10 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 12, Folder 4, Item 156 for print of this negative.
  - Hopedale Street (west side), railroad depot, 1903 (Box 134, Folder 159)
    Negative no.B159. Image depicts part of the west side of Hopedale Street in Hopedale, Massachusetts, showing a small wooden clapboard house on the right, with shutters and curtains at the windows. In the center background is a small, one-story building that is probably the railroad depot. Railroad cars can be seen behind it. To the left is a horse-drawn carriage and two other horses probably hooked to wagons. What appears to be smoke in the air is probably from a railroad engine. In the foreground (on the east side of Hopedale Street) is grass and several trees. Original photograph by the Draper Company. 8 x 10 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 12, Folder 4, Item 159 for print of this negative.
  - Town Hall, Hopedale Street (west side), 1903 (Box 134, Folder 160)
    Negative no.B160. May 12, 1903. Image depicts a three-story stone building situated on the corner of Hopedale Street (in front of the building) and another, unknown street on the right. The building was designed by architect Fred Swasey of Milford and built in 1886; note the cornerstone with the phrase "anno domini" and the date in Roman numerals. The building appears to be in the Romanesque style, somewhat similar to that of H. H. Richardson. The building has two chimneys and a gabled roof with decorative ironwork running along the upper edge. There are three entrances at the front, one of which is to the post office (note the two windows labeled "Post Office") and another to the left to another business. The curved archway is probably the entrance to the town hall itself. See also Box 23, Negative 351. Original photograph by the Draper Company. 8 x 10 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 12, Folder 4, Item 160 for print of this negative.
  - East side of Hopedale Street between Social and Union streets, 1903 (Box 134, Folder 164)
    Negative no.B164. May 12, 1903. Image depicts the east side of Hopedale Street in Hopedale, Massachusetts, between Social and Union streets. It is unclear if Hopedale Street is the unpaved street in the foreground, or if it is the side street on which a number of houses are visible. These houses are substantial two-story wood clapboard buildings; another two-story wood clapboard house is on the right side of the side street. Some open ground or lawn separates that house from the unpaved street in the foreground. Trees line the side street. Original photograph by the Draper Company. 8 x 10 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 12, Folder 4, Item 164 for print of this negative.
  - Hopedale Street (east side) between Social & Union streets, 1903 (Box 134, Folder 165)